[
  {
    "question": "1. What is a string?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) A numeric data type",
      "b) A sequence of characters",
      "c) A collection of nodes and edges",
      "d) A linear data structure"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "2. What is the length of a string?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) The number of characters in the string",
      "b) The number of words in the string",
      "c) The number of lines in the string",
      "d) The number of bytes required to store the string"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "3. Which operation is used to concatenate two strings?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) Concatenation",
      "b) Substring",
      "c) Comparison",
      "d) Extraction"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "4. What is a substring?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
    "options": [
      "a) The first character of a string",
      "b) A string with all characters in uppercase",
      "c) A contiguous sequence of characters within a string",
      "d) A string with all whitespace characters removed"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "5. What is the time complexity of accessing a character at a specific index in a string?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) O(1)",
      "b) O(n)",
      "c) O(log n)",
      "d) O(n^2)"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "6. What is string interpolation?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) Manipulating strings to extract substrings",
      "b) Concatenating strings using a loop",
      "c) Comparing strings based on their lengths",
      "d) Embedding expressions or variables within a string"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "7. What is the purpose of string formatting?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 0,
    "options": [
      "a) To control the appearance and layout of strings",
      "b) To convert strings to numbers",
      "c) To perform mathematical operations on strings",
      "d) To extract characters from strings"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "8. What is a palindrome?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 2,
    "options": [
      "a) A string with all characters in uppercase",
      "b) A string with all whitespace characters removed",
      "c) A string that reads the same backward as forward",
      "d) A string containing only vowels"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "9. Which operation is used to find the index of the first occurrence of a substring within a string?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 3,
    "options": [
      "a) Concatenation",
      "b) Substring",
      "c) Comparison",
      "d) Search"
    ]
  },
  {
    "question": "10. What is string manipulation?",
    "correctAnswerIndex": 1,
    "options": [
      "a) Converting strings to numbers",
      "b) Performing operations on strings to change or extract information",
      "c) Concatenating strings",
      "d) Extracting substrings from strings"
    ]
  }
]